Taylor Wofford

taylor.wofford@gmail.com | (214) 632-8480 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

Skills: CSS3, Express, Git, HTML5, JavaScript, MongoDB, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RSpec, React, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQLite, jQuery

Projects:

Slick — Slick is a pixel-perfect Slack clone built with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React, Redux and WebSockets.

- Implemented Action Cable, Rails' integration of WebSockets, to improve user experience by eliminating polling and unnecessary AJAX queries.
- Built user authentication from the ground up to decrease reliance on third-party libraries.

InStock — InStock allows users to locate hard-to-find products in local stores. It was built with MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js.

- Employed the Google Maps JavaScript API to give users a wealth of options when looking for products.
- Worked with a team of three other developers, specializing in frontend development and graphic design.

Frontend Project

TKNAME is a data visualization of fatal and/or injurious motor vehicle collisions in New York City from 2014 to present. It was built primarily with JavaScript, jQuery and D3.

- Wrote efficient queries in the Socrata Open Data API's SoQL language to create a friendly, fast user experience with a 1.85 gigabyte dataset.
- Crafted crisp, enjoyable maps, graphs and animations with D3.

Experience:

Program Manager, New York City Urban Debate League (September 2017-January 2018)

- Increased quality of programming by implementing data-driven improvement plans.
- Oversaw a \$1 million programming budget.
- Managed a team of four.

Freelance Journalist, Various (November 2013-August 2017)

- Researched and wrote rigorously-sourced feature stories for VICE's Motherboard, Quartz, *Newsweek*, The Outline and Gothamist, among others.
- Won fellowships to travel to Cuba and Japan.

Education:

App Academy (January 2020-May 2020) – intensive software engineering bootcamp with lower than 3 percent acceptance rate.

University of Kansas, Bachelor of Science in Journalism (2005-2009), 4.0 GPA.